<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN" 
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY appversion "1.2">
  <!ENTITY manrevision "1.2">
  <!ENTITY date "October 2008">
  <!ENTITY app "<application>Device Driver Utility 1.2</application>">
  <!ENTITY appname "Device Driver Utility">
]>
<!--
Copyright 2009 Sun Microsystems, Inc. All rights reserved
Use is subject to license terms.
-->
<!-- 
      (Do not remove this comment block.)
  Maintained by the GNOME Documentation Project
  http://developer.gnome.org/projects/gdp
  Template version: 2.0 beta
  Template last modified Feb 12, 2002
  
-->
<!-- =============Document Header ============================= -->
<article id="index" lang="en">
<!-- please do not change the id; for translations, change lang to -->
<!-- appropriate code -->
  <articleinfo> 
    <title>&appname; Manual</title>
    
    <copyright> 
         <year>2009</year> 
      <holder>Sun Microsystems</holder> 
    </copyright> 
<!-- translators: uncomment this:

  <copyright>
   <year>2003</year>
   <holder>ME-THE-TRANSLATOR (Latin translation)</holder>
  </copyright>

   -->
<!-- An address can be added to the publisher information.  If a role is 
     not specified, the publisher/author is the same for all versions of the 
     document.  -->
    <publisher role="maintainer"> 
      <publishername> HCTS Project </publishername> 
    </publisher> 

   <!-- This file  contains link to license for the documentation (GNU FDL), and 
        other legal stuff such as "NO WARRANTY" statement. Please do not change 
	any of this. -->
    
    <revhistory>
    <revision> 
		<revnumber>&appname; Manual V&manrevision;</revnumber> 
		<date>&date;</date> 
		<revdescription> 
	  		<para role="author">HCTS Project</para>
	  		<para role="publisher">HCTS Project</para>
		</revdescription> 
    </revision> 
    </revhistory> 
    <releaseinfo>This manual describes version &appversion; of &appname;.
    </releaseinfo> 
    <abstract role="description">
      <para>User manual for <application>Device Driver Utility</application>.</para>
    </abstract>

  </articleinfo> 

  <indexterm>
    <primary>Device Driver Utility</primary> 
  </indexterm> 

<!-- ============= Document Body ============================= -->

<!-- ============= About DDU ============================== -->
<sect1 id="about-ddu">
  <title>About Device Driver Utility</title>
    <para>Device Driver Utility 1.2</para>
    <para>Copyright 2009 Sun Microsystems, Inc. All rights reserved.</para> 
    <para>U.S. Government Rights - Commercial software. Government users are subject to the Sun Microsystems, Inc. standard license agreement and applicable provisions of the FAR and its supplements.</para>
    <para>Use is subject to license terms.</para>
    <para>This distribution may include materials developed by third parties.Sun, Sun Microsystems, the Sun logo, Java, and Solaris are trademarks or registered trademarks of Sun Microsystems, Inc. in the U.S. and other countries.</para>

    <para>Copyright 2009 Sun Microsystems, Inc. Tous droits réservés.</para> 
    <para>L'utilisation est soumise aux termes du contrat de licence.</para>
    <para>Cette distribution peut comprendre des composants développés par des tierces parties.</para>
    <para>Sun, Sun Microsystems, le logo Sun, Java, et Solaris sont des marques de fabrique ou des marques déposées de Sun Microsystems, Inc. aux Etats-Unis et dans d'autres pays.</para>
</sect1>
<!-- ============= Overview ============================== -->
<sect1 id="ddu-introduction">
  <title>Device Driver Utility 1.2 Overview</title>
    <para>Device Driver Utility 1.2 is an application that provides information about those devices of your native system that have the OpenSolaris 2009.06 Operating System (OS) installed. Device Driver Utility enables you to connect to the Image Packaging System (IPS) and search device drivers for the devices that do not have drivers attached to them. IPS is a repository for the OpenSolaris OS packages. You can find suitable drivers for the devices in this repository. Use the Device Driver Utility application to perform the following functions:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
    <listitem><para>Get information about devices installed on your native system and check whether their corresponding device drivers exist.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem><para>Search the IPS repository for your system devices that do not have corresponding driver attached.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem><para>Download and install the device drivers from the IPS for devices on your system.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem><para>Submit system configurations to HCL.</para>
    </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

<para>Device Driver Utility 1.2 is integrated with the OpenSolaris 2009.06 OS. This utility requires at least Python version 2.4 and Perl version 5.8. However, the OpenSolaris 2009.06 OS is by default integrated with Perl version 5.8 and Python version 2.4.</para>
<para>To report a bug or for any suggestion, send an email to <email>driver-utility-feedback@sun.com</email>.</para>

</sect1>

<!--============== DDU interface ===========-->
<sect1 id="ddu-interface">
  <title>Device Driver Utility 1.2 Interface</title>
    <para>To invoke Device Driver Utility 1.2 click Applications->System Tools->Device Driver Utility on the OpenSolaris 2009.06 OS desktop. The Device Driver Utility window is displayed.
    </para>
 <figure id="DDU_Main_Window">
  <title>Device Driver Utility Main Window</title>
  <screenshot>
    <mediaobject> 
    <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="figures/main.jpg" format="JPG" srccredit="Andreas"/>
   </imageobject>
    <textobject> 
      <phrase>Device Driver Utility Main Window</phrase> 
    </textobject> 
  </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
 </figure>
 <para>
 The Types column shows the device category names. Various device categories are Audio, CPU, DVD, Memory, Network, Storage, USB, Video, and Other. If you are using a laptop, there will be a battery category shown up which gives information about your laptop's battery. The Device column shows the list of controllers and device names corresponding to each device category. The Driver column shows the names of the existing device drivers or the status of the existing device driver for each device.
 </para>
    <para>The status of the device driver can be one of the following:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
    <listitem><para>Driver Missing: Indicates that there is no driver attached to the device.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem><para>Driver Available: Indicates that there is no driver in the system but the driver exists in the IPS.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem><para>Driver Unavailable: Indicates that there is no driver in the system or in the IPS.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem><para>Driver Misconfigured: Indicates that the driver does not function properly.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem><para>Third-party Driver: Indicates that a third-party driver exists for the device.</para>
    </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>The name of the device driver is displayed if the driver exists for the respected device in the system.</para>
    <para>The Device Driver Utility window provides the following buttons:</para> 

    <itemizedlist>
    <listitem><para>Refresh: Directs the system to search for devices. If the status of the device driver is Driver Missing, click the Refresh button. This searches the system for the devices and their corresponding drivers and displays the information. This action might change the previous status of the device driver.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem><para>Help: Displays the online help for Device Driver Utility.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem><para>Close: Closes the Device Driver Utility.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem><para>Submit: Submits the configurations of your system to the OpenSolaris hardware compatibility list (HCL).</para>
    <para>When you click the Submit button, the Submit Information To HCL window is displayed. Type the following system information in the corresponding fields:</para>
<figure id="DDU_Submit_Window">
  <title>Device Driver Utility Submit Window</title>
  <screenshot>
    <mediaobject> 
    <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="figures/submit.jpg" format="JPG" srccredit="Andreas"/>
   </imageobject>
    <textobject> 
      <phrase>Device Driver Utility Submit Window</phrase> 
    </textobject> 
  </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
 </figure>
    
	    <itemizedlist>
	    <listitem><para>System type: Select the type of the system from the drop-down list.</para>
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem><para>Manufacture name: Type the name of the system maker such as Hewlett-Packard  or Dell.</para>
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem><para>Model: Type the complete model number for the system being tested, such as HP xw8400 Workstation.</para>
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem><para>BIOS/Firmware Maker: Type the information on the BIOS Setup screen that is usually displayed while booting the system.</para>
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem><para>CPU type: Type the name of the CPU maker. For instance, Intel(R)Xeon(R)CPU5130@2.00GHz.</para>
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem><para>Information Collected: Verify whether this information reflects the details that you have specified and submit the same to Sun.</para>
            </listitem>
	    <listitem><para>General Notes: Type any additional information of the system whose details are submitted. You can also type the information of how successfully you got the system and components to work with the OpenSolaris OS.</para>
	    </listitem>
	    </itemizedlist>
	    
    </listitem>
    <listitem><para>Install All Drivers: Installs all the missing drivers. The Install All Drivers pop-up window is displayed indicating the progress of installation.</para>
    </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
</sect1>

<!--============== Working with DDU  ===========-->
<sect1 id="ddu-working">
  <title>Working with Device Driver Utility 1.2</title>
    <para>To get the hardware details of your system:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
    <listitem><para>Right click on any device and click Detail Information. The Hardware Detail Information pop-up window is displayed where you can find the details of your system's hardware.</para>
    </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
<figure id="DDU_Detail_Window">
  <title>Device Driver Utility Detail Information Window</title>
  <screenshot>
    <mediaobject> 
    <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="figures/detail.jpg" format="JPG" srccredit="Andreas"/>
   </imageobject>
    <textobject> 
      <phrase>Device Driver Utility Detail Information Window</phrase> 
    </textobject> 
  </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
 </figure>
    <para>To install missing drivers:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
    <listitem><para>Right click on any device and click Install Driver. The Install Driver pop-up window is displayed indicating the progress of installation.</para>
    </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  
  <figure id="DDU_Install_Window">
  <title>Device Driver Utility Install Driver Window</title>
  <screenshot>
    <mediaobject> 
    <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="figures/Install_driver.jpg" format="JPG" srccredit="Andreas"/>
   </imageobject>
    <textobject> 
      <phrase>Device Driver Utility Install Driver Window</phrase> 
    </textobject> 
  </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
 </figure>
 
   <para>To get the details of the third-party drivers:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
    <listitem><para>When you click the Refresh button, Device Driver Utility searches the system to check for the existing device drivers of your system. If a third-party driver exists for the device, the information about the third-party driver including the URL to download is displayed in the Detail Information window.</para>
    </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
       <para>To Submit your System to HCL:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
    <listitem><para>Using Device Driver utility, you can submit your system information to Hardware Compatibility List (HCL) by clicking the Submit button. Upon submission, you will get an acknowledgement of your submission and a link where your submission is available. The Sun auditing team will check and publish your system information to HCL.
</para>
    </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
</sect1>

</article>
